Donald Barthelme Literary Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Works by Barthelme [1959]-1990
  - Snow White, A Play with Music, 1974
    - Copyedited typescript, with corrections (bound) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Straws in the Wind, 1975
    - Program (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Poetry, undated
  Two fragments of poems by Barthelme.
  - Fragments, undated
    - Harder than whale meat... (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Peter Hope... (Box 10, Folder 14)
  Non-Fiction, 1972-1988
  A variety of non-fiction material is gathered in this series. Most of it is essays written for publication, such as the pieces published anonymously in the "Notes and Comments" section of The New Yorker. Some pieces not for publication are also found in this series, such as introductions delivered for other writers and eulogies. Material is primarily in the form of typescripts, galley proofs, and tear sheets.
  - Amphigorey, Also by Edward Gorey, 1983
    - Typescript (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Galley Proof (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - As Grace Paley Faces Jail with Three Other Writers, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Being Bad [Robert Rauschenberg], undated
    - Typescript (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Galley proof (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Rossellen Brown's Fiction, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - The Case of the Vanishing Product, photocopy, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Donald Barthelme on Superman III, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Eulogies, 1978-1979 and undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Exquisite Creatures, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Introductions and Blurbs, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Jim Love Up to Now: An Introduction, 1980
    - Typescript (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Galley proof (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Most Wonderful Trick [John Hawkes], 1984
    - Clipping (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Notes and Comment [New Yorker]
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Galley proofs, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Page proofs (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Tear sheets, 1976-1978 and undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Photocopies, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Not-Knowing, undated
    - Typescripts (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Photocopies (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Galley proofs (Box 25)
  - An Objection [Letter to the Editor], undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - On Houston and Making a Difference (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - On Our Street, 1983
    - Galley proof (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - On the Level of Desire (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Typescript, undated
    - Galley proofs, photocopy, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Real Fakes [Letter to the Editor], 1973 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Remarks, 1972-1981 and undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - The Short-Story Contest [New York Times], 1976
    - Tear sheet (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Slow Slow Slow, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - [Speech on writers delivered at the University of Houston], 1974 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Synergy, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - [Kurt Vonnegut], [Esquire], 1985
    - Tear sheet (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Woman is an imaginary being, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Fragments on writing, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  Related Artwork and Collage Stories, [1970]-1988
  This series includes the artwork and "collage stories" that Barthelme created by gluing engravings, woodcuts, and pieces of clip art to posterboard or other backgrounds. Some loose collage pieces have been reglued to their backgrounds using reversible wheat starch paste.
  - At the Tolstoy Museum, paste up, [1970] (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - The Educational Experience [collage story] (Box 27)
  - The Emerald, [1979] (Box 27)
  - The Inauguration [collage story] (Box 28)
  - The Rook's Progress [with Jim Love], preliminary section, photocopy, [ca. 1988] (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - The Show [collage story], [1970] (Box 28)
  - The Slightly Irregular Fire Engine [children's book]
    - Layout with artwork, [c1971] (Box 26, Folder 1-15)
  - The Story Thus Far [collage story] (Box 28)
  - Fragments (Box 27)
    - My grandfather faints..., undated
    - Untitled, undated
  - Artwork by Donald Barthelme, 1977-1988 and undated (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Artwork by Others, 1980 and undated (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Drawing of Donald Barthelme, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Engravings and Collage Sources, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Loose Collage Pieces, undated (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Transfer Lettering, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1958-1997
  Correspondence written to Donald Barthelme has been arranged alphabetically by the last name of the sender. Whenever a single correspondent had six or more letters in the collection, a separate folder was created. There is one folder of correspondence from Donald Barthelme to others.
  - Roger Angell, 1977-1987 and undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - A, 1975-1987 and undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - John Barth, 1969-1986 and undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Donald Barthelme, 1971-1989 and undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ann Beattie, 1980-1988 and undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Kay Boyle, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Karen Braziller, 1978-1985 and undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - B, 1972-1986 and undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Kenneth Cavander, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Arthur A. Cohen, 1978-1986 and undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Maggie Curran, 1978-1980 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Maggie Curran, 1981-1987 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - C, 1972-1988 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Arthur C. Danto, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Da-Di, 1965-1988 and undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Do-Dz 1979-1989 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - E, 1978-1988 and undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - June Fortress, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Marianne Frisch, 1979-1982 and undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - F, 1975-1983 and undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - David Gates, 1976-1980 and undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Philip Graham, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - G, 1974-1988 and undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Shelby Hearon, 1977-1982 and undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Oscar Hijuelos, 1981-1985 and undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Ha-He,1976-1988 and undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Hi-Hz, 1974-1988 and undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - I-J, 1966-1984 and undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Anna Kolyszko, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - K, 1975-1989 and undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Jim Love, 1979-1987 and undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Beverly Lowry, 1978-1981 and undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - L, 1975-1997 and undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Larry McCaffery, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Margaret Mills, 1978-1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Mc-Ma, 1974-1988 and undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Me-Mz, 1975-1987 and undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cameron and Donna Northouse, 1979-1988 and undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - J.D. O'Hara, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Stathis Orphanos, 1979-1983 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - N-O, 1974-1985 and undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Grace Paley, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Walker Percy, 1965-1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - James Pickering, 1981-1987 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Padgett Powell, 1982-1988 and undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - P, 1973-1989 and undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Q-R, 1974-1988 and undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Ralph B. Sipper, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Roger Straus, 1974-1982 and undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Sa-Sm, 1977-1986 and undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - So-Sz, 1969-1987 and undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Marshall Terry, 1979-1981 and undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - T, 1974-1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - U-V, 1974-1988 and undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Wa-Wh, 1958-1986 and undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Wi-Wz, 1976-1990 and undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Herb Yellin, 1978-1979 and undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - X-Y-Z, 1978-1988 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - From Large Group, 1979-1982 and undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - First Names Only, A-M, 1976-1988 and undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - First Names Only, N-Z, 1978-1985 and undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Inclusions to Letters (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified, 1968-1987 and undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Material about Barthelme and his Works, 1964-2001
  Interviews and Biographical Articles, 1972-2001
  An interview with Barthelme was published in the Summer 1981 issue of the Paris Review as part of its well known series of interviews with writers. J.D. O'Hara taped the initial conversation with Barthelme, transcribed the tape, and sent the transcript to Barthelme. Barthelme heavily reworked the transcript to make an entirely different draft. This series contains various drafts of the interview and some related correspondence. See also the J.D. O'Hara folder in the Correspondence series.
  - The Paris Review
    - Typescript draft, [ca. 1980-1981] (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Second typescript draft (photocopied), with editorial notes by Ann Beattie, [ca. 1980-1981] (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Third typescript draft (photocopied), [ca. 1980-1981] (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Final typescript draft (photocopied), signed, [ca. 1980-1981] (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Page proof, introduction to interview, [ca. 1980-1981] (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, [ca. 1980-1981] (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-2001 and undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Reviews, 1964-1990
  Reviews of Barthelme's works, primarily from newspapers and magazines. Reviews on acidic newsprint have been photocopied onto less acidic paper.
  - Amateurs, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - City Life, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Come Back, Dr. Caligari, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - The Dead Father, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Forty Stories, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Great Days, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Great Days [play], 1983 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Guilty Pleasures, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - The King, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Other Works, 1970-1988 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Overnight to Many Distant Cities, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Paradise, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Sadness, 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Sam's Bar, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Sixty Stories, 1981, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - The Slightly Irregular Fire Engine, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Snow White, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Unspeakable Practices, Unnatural Acts, 1968-69 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  Articles and Reviews, Foreign Language, 1969-1984
  Reviews of Barthelme's work in languages other than English.
  - Articles and Reviews, Foreign Language, 1969-1984 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  Clippings, 1974-1989
  Articles about Barthelme, the Houston/Texas writing scene, and some of his friends.
  - Donald Barthelme, 1974-1989 and undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Houston/Texas Writing Scene, 1984-1988 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Mary Ann Hayes (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Jim Love, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Grace Paley and the White House Eleven, 1978-1979and undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Susan Sontag, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  Criticism/Papers on Barthelme, 1975-1986
  This series contains literary criticism and student papers about Barthelme's work.
  - Criticism/Papers on Barthelme, 1975-1986 and undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
- Writing Career, 1972-1997
  Creative Writing Program, University of Houston, [ca. 1980s-1988]
  This series contains materials related to Barthelme's teaching career at the University of Houston, including some of the assignments he gave his writing classes. The folder containing class enrollment and grades is closed to the public for privacy reasons.
  - Class Enrollment and Grades, 1981-1988 CLOSED (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Class Materials, [ca. 1980s] (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Promotional Materials, Creative Writing Program and Houston Reading Series, [ca. 1980s] (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Promotional flyer paste-ups, 1987-1988 (Box 27)
  - Teaching Evaluations, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - University of Houston, [ca. 1980s] (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Graduate Program in Writing, The City College of New York, [ca. 1970s]
  One folder of material related to Barthelme's teaching career at the City College of New York.
  - Graduate Program in Writing, The City College of New York, [ca. 1970s] (Box 14, Folder 7)
  PEN American, 1976-1989
  Barthelme was a member of the writers' association PEN American Center, serving as its vice president for the period 1977-1979. Most of the material in this series relates to the planning of the 48th International PEN Congress, which was held in New York City in 1986. Copies of papers that were delivered on the topic of "The Writer's Imagination and the Imagination of the State," are included.
  - Awards, 1989 and undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 48th International PEN Congress, Packets, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 48th International PEN Congress, Panelists' Papers, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
  - 48th International PEN Congress, Report, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - PEN American Center, 1978-1987 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - PEN American Center, Printed Manner, 1976-1989 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Planning Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Planning Committee, Planning Survey Results, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Program Committee, 48th International PEN Congress, 1983-1986 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Program Committee, 48th International PEN Congress, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  Awards and Events, 1972-1984
  Awards and certificates received by Barthelme, including the National Book Award and the French Chevalier dans l'Ordre des Arts et des Lettres, and related materials.
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1978-1983 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Chevalier dans l'Ordre des Arts et des Lettres certificate, with letter, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980-1984 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - National Book Award for Children's Books, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, Morton Dauwen Zabel Award, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Writers in Society Series, University of Houston [U-matic videotape]
  Contracts, 1975-1997
  - Contracts, 1975-1997 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  Royalties, 1978-1986
  This folder contains royalty statements.
  - Royalties, 1978-1986 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  Miscellaneous, 1987
  This folder contains only a single membership roster for the Texas Institute of Letters.
  - Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Photographs, 1979-1988
  Photographs of Donald Barthelme alone or with his wife or fellow writers. Of special note is the photograph from the "Postmodernists Dinner" arranged by Barthelme in 1983, which includes leading writers who were described by critics as postmodern in style.
  - John Barth, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Donald and Marion Barthelme, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Donald Barthelme, 1979 and undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Donald Barthelme, [ca. 1980s] (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Donald Barthelme, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Donald Barthelme 1988 (Box 29)
  - Donald Barthelme and John Barth, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Donald Barthelme and Grace Paley, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Donald Barthelme and George Plimpton, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Postmodernists Dinner: Donald Barthelme, John Barth, Robert Coover, Kurt Vonnegut, Walter Abish, William Gass, and others, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous, 1960-1989
  Most notable in this series are biographical notes about Donald Barthelme, and a photocopy of his appointment book from 1979.
  - Art Openings, Promotional Materials, 1978-1987 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Biographical Information, 1982-1987 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Business Cards, Others', undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Cards, Various, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Financial, 1973-1989 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Houston Review Cover (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Magazine Clippings, 1979-1984 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Memorial Services, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Notes and Addresses, undated (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Postcards, Blank, undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Printed Pamphlets, 1960-1983 and undated (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Transcript, University of Houston, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Week-at-a-Glance appointment book, photocopy, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 46)
- Students' Works, 1983-1989
  Graduate Students, Creative Writing Program
  Works submitted to Barthelme by students in the Creative Writing Program at the University of Houston.
  - Elizabeth Ashton
    - The Exorcist, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Street Talk, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - The Triumph 10, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - [Glenn Blake]
    - Chocolate Bay, undated (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
    - The Clearing, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Michael Bond
    - Leftovers (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
    - Maureen Brown
    - Pizza Kid, with note, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - [Kathleen] Cambor
    - Anne, undated (Box 15, Folder 11-13)
    - Stars, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Vikram Chandra
    - Red Earth and Pouring Rain, undated (Box 15, Folder 15-18)
  - [Thomas] Cobb
    - Consider the Lilies of the Field, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Kevin Cunningham
    - Strange Attractors, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Tracy Daugherty
    - Harrup, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Harrup, alternate draft, with note, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Lowrider, with letter, undated (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    - Observatory, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Problem, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Raphael's Blush, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lila Havens
    - Noctimania, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - O[live] Hershey
    - Science in the Modern World, with card, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sabine Hilding
    - Anna, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Anna, alternate draft, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Robert Lunday
    - The Amnesia Club, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Elizabeth McBride
    - Separations (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
    - Sheila, Part I, with cards, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
    - Sheila, Part I, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
  - Daniel C. Massey
    - Local Terror (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - [Virginia] "Ginger" [Moran]
    - The Algebra of Snow (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - David Portz
    - Hand Motions About the Neck, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Short Stories, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Padgett Powell
    - Typical, with note to Marion, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - [Michael] "Mike" Ronan
    - Dali Lama Dreams, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Marilyn Stablein
    - After the Trial, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Circling the Buddha, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Eleanor Totz
    - Defiled, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - George Williams
    - Airport, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Bus, undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Deadly, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Fame, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Garden of Earthly Delights, with letter, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Ghost, undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Mule, with letter, undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Under a Green Sun, undated (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Eric Miles Williamson
    - The Pedestrian Wheel, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Paul Yeager
    - Red Hot Nights, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Red Hot Nights, alternate draft (photocopy), with letter, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - George?
    - The History of Luminescence (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
  - [Polly]
    - Roberta 1956, ch. 7, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified
    - Angel Corp., undated (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
    - The Butterfly Effect, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - The Heater Man, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - [L.A. Law teleplay], undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Rates of Exchange, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Slam Dance, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Fragments, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  Undergraduate Students, 1984-1988
  Works submitted to Barthelme by undergraduate students at the University of Houston.
  - Undergraduate students, 1984-1988 and undated (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
  - Fragments, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Works by Others, 1975-1989
  Primarily typescripts and photocopies of works by other writers. A galley proof of William Gass' On Being Blue is included in this series.
  - Roger Angell
    - Remarks, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Ann Beattie
    - Alex Katz (photocopy) with letter, [1987] (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - [Thomas] Benjamin
    - "Free Advice to a Young Composer," 1980 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Arthur C. Danto
    - Philosophizing Literature (two photocopies), undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - John Domini
    - Eastertime Fogs (photocopy), 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Highway Trade (photocopy), 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - The Rules of Dancing (photocopy), 1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - William Gass
    - On Being Blue, galley proof, 1975 (Box 25)
  - Albert Guérard
    - "The View from the Persimmon Tree: Houston 1924-1972," The Touch of Time: Myth, Memory, and the Self, [1980] (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Kenneth Koch
    - Youth, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - George Manner
    - Placement of Things, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Gina Maranto
    - Shadow Keepers, with letter, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Maurice Natanson
    - The Ghost of Perception (photocopy) (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - An Ordinary Evening in New Haven (photocopy) (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - The Sleep of Bad Faith (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Grace Paley
    - Friends (photocopy), undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Photographing/In Another Country/Somewhere Else, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Gregory Blake Smith
    - From The Flesh and the Spirit, [1988] (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Joy Williams
    - (Concerning the Visiting Faculty Person), [spoof of Barthelme's "Concerning the Bodyguard"], undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Robert Wren
    - Harmattan Light, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Love Among the Ruins, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - University, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Dust Jackets, 1976-1981 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Partial Index of Correspondents
  - Angell, Roger
  - Apple, Max
  - Banks, Russell, 1940-
  - Barth, John, 1930-
  - Barthelme, Donald, 1907-1996
  - Beattie, Ann
  - Boyle, Kay, 1902-1992
  - Cheever, John
  - Coover, Robert
  - Dahl, Roald
  - De Kooning, Elaine
  - Fisher, M.F.K. (Mary Frances Kennedy), 1908-1992
  - Gates, David, 1947-
  - Gill, Brendan, 1914-1997
  - Giroux, Robert
  - Hannah, Barry
  - Hess, Thomas B.
  - Hijuelos, Oscar
  - Johnson, B. S. (Bryan Stanley), 1933-1973
  - Lowry, Beverly
  - Macdonald, Cynthia
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938-
  - Paley, Grace
  - Percy, Walker, 1916-1990
  - Powell, Padgett
  - Pynchon, Thomas
  - Shawn, William
  - Sontag, Susan, 1933-2004
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra, 1884-1979
  - Updike, John
  - Vonnegut, Kurt
  - Williams, Joy, 1944-